LTX video 2.3 is released.
And honestly,
I think this model is a huge improving
quality to LTX 2.0.
But how can you run it on your local PC?
And there's so many people trying to
figure it out.
>> You know,
the traditional method is using comfy
UI. But there are so many different
versions and workflows.
>> Waiting hours just to see a crash?
Nah, man.
Comfy UI ain't worth the headache.
>> What you should try is this one, 1 2 GP.
It's easy to install and automatically
downloads everything.
>> One click generation. Just sit back and
wait.
The program does all the hard work for
you.
>> All the footage you see right now was
generated through LTX 2.3 via 1 2 GP.
720p, 10 seconds, only take 2 minutes.
>> If you want to learn how to do this in 5
minutes, stay tuned.
>> We're now in the 1 2 GP interface. This
is a web-based UI. And please be aware
this video is not to teach you how to
generate better results by using 1 2 GP
and that will be next video. And so once
you get to interface, just come to here,
choose LTX 2 and 2.3 22B distilled
version. And you can choose text prompt
or video to image or continue video. All
right, so we're going to stick to text
prompt only just as a demonstration. And
then you come here, you just type in
your prompt. And this is my prompt that
I've prepared. And then under here you
change your resolution. So depends on
your hardware, you can go for 1080p,
720p yes. I suggest starting with the
480p just to experiment. I will I will
stay with a 720p and then in here you
can change all your resolutions.
And now this is the time how long you
want to generate. I want to generate
10-second videos. And
and everything else let's just leave as
default. And all you need to do is just
hit it generate. And that's all to what
now the 12 GP Python script will do all
the heavy lifting. And then if this is
the first time you're running this
software, you have to wait for the LTX 2
2.3 to load and you will it's about 50
GB
so it will take us some time, but just
have a coffee, come back, it will be
done. And now we're just waiting for the
generate.
And so here is my setup. As you guys can
see
the 12 GP has put lots of files under my
RAM. So as I can see the RAM is being
almost full. So 30 GB
RAM has been used. And now if you if you
have a lower VRAM machine, come to
configuration,
performance, and under here is you can
choose a different kind of profile. So
I'm choosing the number one, but then if
you have a different VRAMs, like say if
you have only 8 GB of VRAM or something,
choose the lower profile. And once you
choose the one you liked,
and don't forget to save the settings.
Well, the wait is over. So the video is
generated and let's have a look.
>> LTX video 2.3 is released.
And honestly,
I think this model is a huge improving
quality to LTX 2.0.
>> Oh, that. I think I think the overall
quality is good, but there's definitely
room for improvement because we're using
720p. I think 1080p will be better. You
can still see a little bit teeth um kind
of morphing.
But then let's have a look the result.
So,
overall it takes 241 frames, 10 seconds,
24 frame 24 FPS of frame. I think I
heard people saying if you bump it to
six frames per seconds, you get much
better smooth motion. And the most
important part is guys, look at this.
So, the whole process only take 2
minutes on my um local computer and this
is the unheard of.
Um and then I think LTX 2 can do it, but
this is a huge leap forward. And and the
whole 1 2 GP is pretty much uh you can
works out of the box. Just come in
typing a prompt and hit generate getting
your VRAM setting right and then it's
pretty much generates automatically. If
you want to learn how to install the 1 2
GP to run LTX 2.3 on your own computer,
uh I'm going to show you guys now. It's
Hey guys, LTX 2.3 video engine just
released. And 1 GP team yesterday on the
March 7th has officially supporting LTX
2.3 from the day zero. All you guys
loved my last LTX 2 and 1 2 GP video, so
it's time to make another one. And to
install it, now we have to do the manual
mode. There's no more one click
Pinocchio anymore. I think it's better
this way because we can easily update
it.
So, first click installation.
And depends on if you have Nvidia or
AMD. I have Nvidia, so click
installation guide. You might need to
log in your GitHub account to access the
installation guide for some unknown
reason.
So, once you are in here, you can see
all the stuff you need to do. So, first
we go get download. So, you need to
install get. All right.
And once you install Git, you have to
create a folder named 1 to GP,
then open it, right click, select open
in terminal, and copy paste the
following commands. All right, let's go.
I get to my D drive,
right click,
folders,
1 2
GP.
And right click,
open in terminals.
Now, let's clone this command. Git
clone.
Come to back to your terminal, paste
that, and run it.
Well, that should be done.
Let's have a look.
Yeah, so
So, it's under 1 to GP and 1 to GP
again.
Okay. All right, now I can see you now
have all the files here.
The next step is creating Python
environment using conda. Well,
unfortunately, I don't have conda, so I
have to install it. So, come to here,
they have a mini conda download. Let's
click this link.
And you should start downloading.
Already done.
All right, let's run this installation.
Next, I agree.
Uh install for just me.
Next.
All right,
install the conda. All right, now that's
complete. Click next.
And finish. And now let's copy this
code, conda create. So, pretty much
create a Python environment. So, now
we're going to your Windows search a lot
conda prompt, and open this one.
And wait for it to load.
And then paste the same prompt.
The conda create.
and paste that. Do you accept the term
of service?
Yes, we accept.
Do you accept term of service?
And yes, we accept.
And now they're telling you the
following new
package will be installed. Do you want
to install? Yes.
And now we have create the environment.
So, next one is we have to activate the
1 2 GP conda environment. So, copy
this one
and come to your
Anaconda prompt. Don't get it wrong.
And paste that.
And just hit enter.
And now we are under When you see you
have 1 2 GP in the front, means we have
entered the room of this conda
environment. So, that's all done.
Oh, and then now we choose Now, the next
step will be choose the installation
according to you GPU.
All right, so
So, guys, you can go through this.
Depends on which GPU you have.
And I have a 3000 series. So, Windows
installation for RTX 3000 series. So,
then this is what we need to do. So, I'm
using this installation. And please
note, do not paste this command into
your
PowerShell. No, no, big no, no. We have
to come to
the Anaconda prompt. And then you have
to see there's 1 2 GP in front of it.
Otherwise, it will be installed into
your Windows, which you don't want that.
You want it to install under 1 2 GP
conda environment. So, let's just paste
that.
And hit enter.
And that will be pretty straightforward
from now on. So, now we just wait for
you to download.
And as you can see, the file is 2.5 GB.
So, it takes some time to download. All
right, the first command has been
complete. Now, let's
let's install the second command. Just
uh copy-paste one.
And come back to your Anaconda
prompt.
And paste pip install.
And then hit enter.
And now we have to wait again.
All right, that was quick. And now let's
come to the third step, which is install
Sage to attention.
All right, let's copy this.
And
paste. And then All right, so Sage
attention has been installed. That was
pretty quick.
And now we're down to the last steps.
And then copy that.
Again, paste.
And now I hit a error message. So, now
we're hitting a error message. I think
because in the in this environment, we
do not have the requirement TXT files.
So, we need to So, remember in the first
we installed a 1-2-GP in the D drive.
So, it's actually 1-2-GP and then 1-2-GP
folder. So, you need to type in where it
is. Look here, guys. So, and then type
in the same code as this one, just
change your directory to where you
install 1 2 GP, and then hit enter.
And so, now we are in 1 2 GP, and then
we change directory to D drive to 1 2 GP
and 1 2 GP. And now we can run the PP
install.
And
And then you will install everything we
require for the RTX 3000 cards. All
right, so now the whole installation has
been complete. After installation
complete, now it's time to start the
engine. So, let's type in this code. All
right, guys, so now we just have to
wait.
And
in the first time you starting, they
will need to downloading some files.
So, we'll we'll come back and have a
coffee and come back and check.
First time you open, I waited for about
3 minutes. Don't Do not worry. So, now
we should be able to launch our local
web UI.
All right, copy that and paste.
And here we go, guys. So, 1 GP version
10.981
is officially installed. And now let's
check for LTX 2.3. So, under LTX 2,
click on LTX 2.3 22B,
and choose the distilled version,
and
attention mode is auto seg 2, data type
is FB16.
And same user face as before. All right,
guys, so now we're in. So, the first
time when you trying to use this model,
they need to downloading some essential
files, and it will take a lot of time.
So, um
let's just use the default setting for
everything.
All right, guys, hope you guys enjoyed
this video. If this video helps you in
any way, please don't forget to like and
subscribe to the channel. I'll close the
this video now and start to stress
testing the LTX 2.3. And once I found
out the tips and tricks, I'll upload
another videos and stay tuned.